Come on, Papa Toad!
We're gonna be late!
Okay, okay, I'm coming!
Here is surely a beautiful heart!
I'm putting up my heart in my dreams!
I'm going to get high!
My body is not a force!
I'm going to hold my hand!
I'm going to get a little
bit of my thoughts!
I'm going to get up my mind!
Okay, hold up a second!
What are friends for?
I was surprised you called, though.
I mean, aren't you, like,
good at sports and stuff?
Ugh.
With water sports, I suck in
both the real and virtual worlds.
Poor Sheyta Toe.
To have to go see the counselor
on a perfect swimming day?
Talk about unlucky.
Yeah, tell me about it.
And after I studied my butt
off this whole first semester.
Too bad, because you're going to miss
out on seeing us in our swimsuits.
But even though you'll be
with that sexy counselor,
that doesn't mean you
can leer at her instead.
Uh, it's not my fault the counselor's hot.
Kiriko
No, I didn't mean it like that.
Um, anyway, I better get going.
Sugu, you're in good hands with them, so
listen to what they say and do your best.
Okay.
The pool here might not be
as deep as the sea in Alpine,
but it's a good place to start.
Just have fun and you'll
be swimming in no time.
Good luck up there, Kirito!
Say hi to the sexy counselor!
Yes?
It's Kazuto, ma 'am.
Mr. Kikuoka.
Hey there, Kirito.
Long time no see.
You're with the virtual
reality section, so, I mean,
no offense, but why are you here? Simple.
I have a couple of things I
wanted to ask you in person,
so I arranged to set up this meeting.
Then, this has nothing
to do with my grades.
No, it doesn't.
Sorry about that, but it was the
only way I'd be sure you'd show up.
I'll leave you two alone now.
If you need me, I'll be
right next door, okay?
Might as well make yourself comfortable.
Please, have a seat.
I hope this won't take long.
I got plans later, so the faster
I get out of here, the better.
Oh, it won't take too long.
I'm trying to wrap up the
SAO and ALO incidents,
but there's a few things I need to check.
So I figured the best way to
do that was to have a sit-down.
I've been over it a million
times with you guys already.
Can't you just check
the player action logs?
They pretty much spell everything out.
Yeah, not quite.
All we can get from the logs are
who went where on any given day.
As for what really happened in
there, we still have no idea.
We don't know the overall picture yet.
4,000 people died in
the game, but for what?
If Akihiko Kayaba were still alive, I'd
be wasting his afternoon instead of yours.
It's important we find out what
Kayaba's motives really were.
I want to know the reason why
he'd make a death game like SAO.
I think if I listen to your
story, the whole thing,
I might be able to get the answers I need.
So, you're gonna help me out or what?
And if I say no.
When all those nerve gears were being rounded
up for disposal, who let you keep one?
Oh, and who told you what
hospital Asuna was in?
And whose department's keeping the
survivors of SAO out of the media spotlight?
Truth is, we've done a lot for you.
Hmm.
Hey, you guys.
Are you sure it's okay for me to use the
pool even though I don't go to your school?
Yep, we got permission.
Our school is your school.
Wow, Rika, your swimsuit's so cool!
I know, right?
I had to get a new one because I
wasn't this boobalicious before SAO.
My old suit was so tight on me.
I wish I could say the same.
I hardly changed at all.
Whoa, look at Asuna rocking the bikini.
Trying to hypnotize
Kirito with stripes, eh?
No, that's not why I wore it.
Ugh, this sucks.
I didn't know I could wear
a normal swimsuit here.
Uh, I mean, you said we were going
to use your school's pool, so...
Your swimsuit looks totally cute, though.
Yeah, totally.
It's so you, Suguha.
What the heck's that supposed to mean?
Okay, where do you want me to start?
I guess the best place would be
the day everyone got trapped.
The date was, uh, what was it?
November 6, 2022.
God, it's already been
two and a half years.
Attention, players.
I welcome you to my world.
What's he mean by that?
My name is Akihiko Kayaba.
And as of this moment, I am
in control of this world.
Seriously?
Is that really cool?
Wow, that's some entrance.
I'm sure most of you have already noticed
an item missing from your main menus,
the logout button.
Let me assure you, this is
not a defect in the game.
I repeat, this is not a defect.
This is how Sword Art
Online was designed to be.
He's kidding, right?
It's important you remember the following.
There is no longer any way to
revive someone within the game.
If your HP drops to zero, your avatar
will be deleted from the system forever.
And the Nerve Gear will
simultaneously destroy your brain.
There's only one way for
a player to escape now.
You must clear the game.
Right now, you're gathered on floor
one, the lowest level of Aincrad.
If you can get through the
dungeon and defeat the boss,
you may advance to the next floor.
Defeat the boss on floor 100
and you will clear the game.
What's he talking about?
Why should we believe any
of the crap you're saying?
We can't clear all hundred floors.
It's freaking impossible.
Even the beta testers
never made it that high!
Last but not least,
I've placed a little present in
the item storage of every player.
Please, have a look.
A mirror?
Klein!
You okay, Kirito? Yeah.
Wait.
who are you i'm me who are you
son of a you're a guy not 17.
wait a second is that you kirito but how
the scan there's a high Density signal
device inside the nerve
gear rig it can see
what my face looks like but how's it know?
My height and body type
when you first put the
nerve gear on it had to
do this calibration thing!
It asked you to touch your body
all over like this remember?
Oh yeah you're right that's where!
It got our physical
data but this is what's
the point why would anyone do this to us?
I think he's about to tell us right
now you're probably wondering why?
Why would Akihiko Kayaba, developer of
Sword Art Online and NerveGear, do this?
Ultimately, my goal was a simple one.
The reason I created Sword Art Online was
to control the fate of
a world of my design.
Kayaba.
As you can see, I have achieved my goal.
He made it to control the fate
of a world of his design, huh?
That's the reason Gabe
gave you guys? Yeah.
So, what'd you think when
you heard him say that?
I don't know.
I guess all I could think about
was how it was going to survive.
There wasn't really time to
think about anything else.
That's why I ditched Klein.
To survive.
Okay.
If that's what you want, I'll get going.
But if you're in a jam,
message me, okay? Sure.
I'll be seeing you, Klein.
Take care.
Kirito!
I...
Hey, Kirito.
You look better like this.
Way cooler than your avatar.
Yeah, and I think that scruffy face
fits you ten times better, too.
I got this!
I can do this!
This world can't beat me!
I will survive!
Woohoo!
We got the pool all to ourselves!
This is going to be so much fun!
Last one in the running!
Wait up, Liz!
Shouldn't you stretch before going in?
Oh, whatever. Here I come!
Okay, okay, you win!
Oh, wow!
That's so cold!
You sneak that dorky thing in here.
You can't learn to swim Even if you're
stuck inside one of these things.
No, don't let the air out of it!
I'll sink if I don't have a floaty thing!
You won't sink.
Especially with the floaty things
you're packing in your swimsuit.
What are you doing? Stop it!
You're so plump and firm.
What are you beneath me?
What's your secret?
Come on, stop it!
Lisbeth?
Sorry about that.
Why don't we start by getting you
used to having your face in the water?
Sound good?
After the big revelation,
most players teamed up in parties,
figuring that was their best
chance at surviving SAO.
But you didn't do that.
You were a solo player pretty
much up until the very last phase.
You knew you'd die for
real if your HP hit zero,
so why would you take that kind of risk?
I didn't start out wanting to.
It was just...
something that happened.
Stop cheering!
Why'd you do it, huh?
Why'd you let Diabel die?
Let him die?
That's what I said! Admit it!
You knew the technique
the boss was gonna use!
You could have told us!
Then Diabel would have stood a chance!
He wouldn't have had to die!
I know why he knew!
He used to be a beta tester!
Think about it!
He knew the boss's attack patterns!
He knew, but he kept it from us!
And I bet he's not the
only beta tester here.
Come on, show yourselves!
So you guys think I used
to be a beta tester.
It's not cool to put me in the
same class with those noobs.
What'd you say?
You heard me.
Most of the thousand people who scored
a slot in SAO's beta were rookies.
They were so green, they didn't
even know how to level up.
Hell, even you guys are
better than they were.
But me, I'm nothing like those guys, man.
During the beta, I made it to floors that
were higher than any of the other testers.
That's a fact.
I knew about the boss,
because I fought tons of monsters with
way more sword skills on higher floors.
I know a bunch of other things, too.
More than you can imagine.
More than any info broker.
What the hell?
If that's true, then you're
worse than a beta tester.
You're a goddamn cheater!
That's what you are!
He's a beta tester and a cheater!
He's a beater!
A beater.
Yeah, that's good. I like it.
Okay.
You can call me a beater.
Just make sure you don't confuse
me with those beta testers anymore.
Oh, okay.
I didn't know you were the inspiration
for that weird beater handle.
Playing the villain was brilliant.
By doing that, you took the
heat off the other beta testers.
Must have been hard to
take that on, though.
Nah, it wasn't all that bad.
Stacia!
Chirico!
Chirico! Sachi!
The hard part
was making friends and
having to watch them die.
Nice job.
You getting used to it yet?
Yeah, I think I'm getting the hang of it.
Still having a hard time opening
my eyes underwater, though.
That part's always weird.
But don't worry, you'll get used to it.
Why don't we take a little break now?
Roger!
It's definitely summer.
It totally is, isn't it?
Isn't it supposed to always be
summer in that quest we're going on?
Yeah, it's in the southern
part of Soph territory.
I heard it gets pretty hot there.
I heard it's loaded with
all kinds of new traps.
I can't wait!
We better figure out a
way to keep Kirito from
going aggro and leaving
us all in the dust again.
Hey, I've been meaning to
ask you guys something.
When you were stuck in the game,
how did you all meet my brother?
I was surrounded by a
bunch of monsters and he
saved me just as I was
about to get attacked.
Pina! Pina! Pina!
Pina!
Head!
Oh, my God.
Peter...
Why would you do all this for me?
I'll tell you, but only if you
promise not to laugh, okay?
I promise I won't.
All right.
It's because you look
like my little sister.
I'm sorry.
Only Kirito would say
something as goofy as that.
I mean, compared to you, Suguha,
Keiko doesn't look a thing like you.
What about us are you comparing?
Anyway, after that, Kirito took me on a
quest to find a rare item to save Pina.
Go ahead, pick it up.
You sure it'll bring Pina
back to life? Uh-huh.
I'm so glad.
There's a bunch of strong
monsters lurking around here.
Let's revive it when we get back to town.
I'm sure Pina would want it that way.
Calm down!
That thing's not that strong!
Help you! Don't save me!
But don't look! Save me!
But don't look!
That'll be... difficult. Help me down!
No! No!
Do you see anything?
When I first met your brother,
it wasn't half as dramatic
as what happened to Silica.
Welcome to Lizbeth's blacksmith shop.
Oh, hi.
I was wondering if you do custom orders.
He doesn't look like
he has that much money.
I can.
The thing is, metal prices
are kind of high these days.
Oh, well, I'm not worried about the cost.
I just want the best sword you
can make as soon as possible.
Well, I make a lot of different swords,
but if you have any idea of the quality
of swords you want, I can make it.
Uh, sure. One sec.
So, I'm looking for something either the
same quality or better than this. Oh.
An elucidator!
monster drop.
What do you think?
How about this?
It's the best sword I ever forged.
I call it my
masterpiece.
I don't know.
It's a little light.
It should be.
I used a speed type metal to forge it.
I'd like to test it if
it's cool. Test it how?
You know, it's durability.
What the heck are you doing?
If you break your sword,
I'm not responsible.
If it breaks, then that's too bad!
He just walked in and
destroyed my best sword.
Talk about a bad first impression.
I'm sorry about that.
That's how he is, though.
Always doing the one thing
you'd least expect. Yeah,
like the time we fell into
a dragon's lair and he
handed me a pile of its poop
like it was no big deal.
Definitely not a good memory.
I'm with you there, Liz. No.
Actually, there were some good memories.
It's so warm.
Huh?
Even though you and me are just these
ones and zeros in a virtual world.
I know.
Look at that!
Kirito!
You know what?
No, what?
Don't freak out!
But I'm falling in love with you!
I can't hear a thing!
What did you just say?
Never mind!
Do me a favor, okay?
Tell Asuna what you told me.
Liz...
I'm fine, really.
The getting over it part,
that's gonna take a while.
Until I do, promise me.
Promise me you'll put
an end to this world.
Till then, I'll keep doing what I do best.
I don't know.
Damn him.
I bet he's flirting with that
cute counselor right now.
You see that? Right there. What? Where?
Right there, see?
What am I looking at?
Those coordinates, there.
I see a boss raid, all the high-level
players, and who do you think that is?
I thought so.
There you are, the strongest
solo player in the game,
joining a raid party to fight a boss.
I'm sure you understand why I
was surprised to see you there.
Well, you shouldn't be.
With four bosses, being a high-level
solo player didn't mean jack.
You needed help.
There were bosses that posed a
threat, even if you were in a party.
Like Illfang the Kobold
Lord, the floor wand boss.
His level was so high,
he almost wiped us out.
Diago, no!
Watch out!
You're going down!
There was Gleam Eyes,
the boss on floor 74.
I beat it using my dual-wielding skill.
But I came this close to getting
myself killed in the process.
Okay, here goes.
Starburst stream!
What the hell kind of skill is that?
Faster!
Gotta go faster!
And that was just the bosses.
But in Aincrad, there was
something even scarier.
Yeah?
What was that?
The other players.
Seriously?
Yeah.
The bosses' parameters were intimidating.
But in the end, they were just programs.
Once you figured out their attack
patterns, you could deal with them.
And since they couldn't leave their
dungeons, you could always bail.
But players, red players, were human too.
And they were always coming
up with new ways to PK you.
And they killed lots of players.
We've been poisoned.
Why do you keep struggling?
Are you afraid of dying after all?
No, I'm just not ready yet.
Is that so?
That's the way I like it!
Die! Die! Die!
It wasn't just the fights
with red players, either.
I found myself in hairy situations
and straight up duels, too.
We may be the top guild, but we barely
get by with the amount of troops we have.
His shield?
Your reaction time is very impressive.
Now's my chance!
Right, Heathcliff, the leader of
the Knights of the Blood Oath.
He was brilliant, one of
the top players in the game.
Yeah, and what's ironic is,
it was my duel with him that tipped
me off about his true identity.
I made a little something for
everyone, so dig in! No way!
Um, I brought along
some lunch to share too.
Help yourselves, do whatever you want.
Thanks for the food!
Who's it from?
Kirito.
He says to start without him.
Okay, then.
I'll just put Kirito's
share in my stomach, too.
You can't eat up all his food.
That's mean.
We have to leave some for him, too.
Okay.
Wow.
Asuna's lunch is so adorable.
I wonder if that's the
kind of girl Kazuto likes.
It's the kind that are all
feminine and can cook good.
Is something wrong,
Suguha? Huh? Oh, nothing.
I was just wondering how you
and my brother met at all.
He never told me, so...
Yeah, tell us how you guys met. Really?
Oh, come on.
We just told you, so it's only fair.
She's right.
You're the only one here who
hasn't talked about it yet.
Well, since you put it
that way... Yeah, right!
So, we first met in a town called Tolbana.
It was on floor one at a boss raid
meeting, and I sort of brushed him off.
At the time, all I could think
about was clearing the game.
You really think these taste good? Uh-huh.
Since I came to this town, I end
up eating at least one a day.
Of course, I got a trick
to make it taste better.
What trick?
Try it with some of that.
Cream?
He taught me that even though
we were stuck in Aincrad,
we could still find ways to enjoy life.
Oh, hey. What's up?
Everyone in the assault team's working
their butts off to clear the dungeon.
And where do I find you?
Out here, taking a nap.
Even if you're a solo player,
you should take this more soon.
Bet you didn't know this
is Aincrad's nicest season.
Today's weather is at its optimal setting.
Huh?
It'd be a waste to have to go
to work on a day like this.
Whatever.
I can't believe you.
Do you even understand what's going on?
Every day here is another
one lost in the real world.
Yeah, but right now, we're
not in the real world, are we?
We're alive in Aincrad.
See?
Doesn't that breeze feel good?
And the sun.
Oh, come on.
The weather's always the same here.
If you laid down on the grass for
a little bit, you'd understand.
Oh, my God.
Oh, damn.
Would you look at that.
Taking a nap in the middle of the day.
Some people sure got it easy.
Couple of lazy losers, man.
I can't believe she fell asleep.
Good morning.
You slept like a rock.
You get one meal.
One meal.
All you can eat, my treat.
Then we'll be even. Deal?
If everything happened
the way you just said,
then it sounds like you fell for
Kitty till before he fell for you.
N-No, it wasn't like...
Uh, don't deny it.
Remember when you came to
get your sword sharpened?
You were all sad because you
thought he wasn't into you.
So how'd you snag him?
Did you chase him down
and confess your feelings?
Well...
So, where am I going to cook it?
Oh, well...
I'm guessing not your place, right?
You even own any cookware?
Okay,
because the main ingredient is special,
I won't have a problem if
we used my place this time.
Good.
So, what do you say you
and me team up again?
Black's my lucky color this week anyway.
Hold up a sec.
Don't you have stuff you
have to do for your guild?
You can't just bail on him.
It's not like we have any
leveling quotas to meet.
Well, then what about your bodyguard?
I'll just ditch him.
The front lines are dangerous, though.
Okay, fine.
Whoa, I didn't think you'd
be that aggressive about it.
Maybe you have to be that aggressive
to get a guy to pay attention.
What could I do?
After all, I was in love with him.
Aw, that's the sweetest
thing I've ever heard.
So, how far'd you guys go, huh?
I know it was in-game, but
you weren't married, so...
Did you?
Or did you?
I'm sorry.
This was...
all my fault, wasn't it?
Asuna...
I'm sorry.
But I...
I should...
stay away from you.
For your sake.
Asuna, my life belongs to you.
I'll give it up for you!
I want to stay with you until the end.
And I promise I'll do anything
to protect you, too. Forever.
No matter what.
I swear.
I'll do everything I can to make
sure you get back to the real world.
Asuna, could I stay
with you for the night?
Don't look.
Not yet, anyway.
What are you waiting for?
Get undressed.
Don't just sit there.
It's embarrassing.
Hey, what are you smiling about?
I was just having a
dream about my old life.
It was weird, and the dream
I had, everything in Aincrad,
everything that happened in meeting you was
just that, a dream, and I was so scared,
but it wasn't.
Thank God it wasn't.
Now that sounds weird.
Don't you want to go back?
Of course I do.
I do, it's just, I don't want my
life here to disappear is all.
The last two years have
been very special to me.
I realize that now.
Listen, Kirito, I was thinking, maybe we
could leave the front lines for a while.
What?
I'm scared.
I feel like if we return to the battlefield
now, something bad's gonna happen again.
Or maybe I'm just tired of it all.
I know what you mean.
I guess I am too.
In the southwest of Floor 22,
there's this tiny little
village by a lake and a forest.
We could get a house together, and then...
And then what?
Then...
We get married.
Okay.
Hello, Earthda Asuna.
Huh? Nothing!
I mean, we didn't!
I mean, we didn't do anything!
Man, I'm so jealous.
You're so lucky being all married
and having Yui, the cutest kid ever.
She is great.
Our pride and joy. Look at you.
You're quite the doting
parent for a teenager.
I think I'll take that
as a compliment, Smartie.
Seriously, we want to make Yui happy, too,
so we'll do our best on today's quest.
A-una-ki-to?
Try to remember.
What were you doing in the forest?
And do you know where
your mom and dad are now?
I don't know.
They can't remember anything.
Oh, no.
Well, you're awake.
Can I call you, Yui?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Then you can call me Kirito.
Can you say Kirito?
Kirito.
It's Kirito.
That's okay.
Maybe it's a little hard.
How about you call me
whatever's easier for you?
Daddy.
Me?
Oh, nice.
Mommy.
Okay.
I'm Mommy. That works.
Mommy!
Mommy! Daddy!
You must be hungry.
Now, what about breakfast?
Okay.
Yui? Yui.
Daddy.
Mommy.
Don't worry.
I remember everything.
Mental Health Counseling
Program Prototype 1.
Codename Yui.
That is who I am.
You aren't just some program anymore.
The system can't control you.
Listen, if you want something,
all you have to do is say it.
Go ahead, tell us what you want.
What I want...
I want...
I want to stay with you forever!
Daddy! Mommy!
You will.
We'll be together forever, Yui.
Yeah.
Remember, you're our child.
Are you okay?
What's this?
The system was about to reject
Yui's admin credentials.
The only thing I could do was take her
program and turn it into a game object.
So this is...
You're holding Yui's heart.
That's amazing.
He never told me about
how you met Yui in SAO?
That's how it happened.
And ever since then, she's been our child.
Okay.
Let's get back in the pool
and practice some more!
Come on, Shiguha.
A couple more lessons and you'll
be swimming circles around Kirito.
Cool.
It's good to be young, isn't it?
I hope those girls realize how lucky
they are to be back in the real world.
They'd be dead if it weren't
for your heroic actions.
I wasn't trying to be a hero.
You figured out Heathcliff was
Akihiko Kayaba, didn't you?
If beating him at his own game wasn't
a heroic act, I don't know what is.
It didn't seem like it
at the time, though.
I'm sorry, Asuna.
Please, keep living.
Game over, Kirito.
Asuna...
You can't...
You can't be...
I'm sorry.
Goodbye.
It's...
over now.
I believe in you, Kirito.
Not yet.
We did it.
Didn't we?
On November 7th at 2.55pm,
the game has been cleared.
Repeat, the game has been cleared.
The report states that after Kayaba
lost the final battle with you,
his brain was fried instantly
by his nerve gear rig.
The autopsy on him confirmed as much.
However, there's one
thing that puzzles me.
You were killed in-game before
he was, and yet you survived.
Was that due to a system-related
reason, or was it the will of Kayaba?
A stunning view, isn't it?
Akihiko Kayaba.
At Argus Headquarters,
the SAO mainframe is in a room
five floors below street level,
and right now it's deleting
all the data from its drives.
In about ten minutes, everything in
this world will disappear forever.
And all the players?
What happens to them?
You don't have to worry about them.
The 6,147 players who survived the game up
to now were logged out a few seconds ago.
And what about the 4,000 people who died?
What about them?
They'll never return.
In any world, real or virtual,
once you're dead, you're gone.
Why?
What's the point?
Why did you do this?
That's a good question.
It's been so long I've
forgotten the reason.
Isn't that strange?
Even before I developed a system for the
full-dive environment, I dreamed of this.
A castle in a world that wasn't governed
by earthly laws and restrictions.
I poured my life into
making that world a reality.
I created this world,
and I got to see something that surpassed
anything I could have imagined for it.
My steel castle floating
in the sky I don't remember
how old I was when I became
obsessed with it I wanted
to leave the earth to fly
to that castle I wanted that
more than anything else for
as long as I can remember
You know what Kirito I want to believe
it's still out there that somewhere in some
other world my castle is still standing
taller than ever Yeah maybe it still is
Before I forget congratulations
on clearing the game Kirito Asuna
Well then I should probably get going now
And that was it?
Kayaba just left you two standing there?
He never gave you a reason
why he made SAO a death game?
Other than that castle story? No.
That's all he said.
Who's that from?
Let me guess—it's from your princess.
When I think of what happened to the
two of you after you survived SAO,
it must have been quite an ordeal.
It was thanks to a certain someone.
A crime was being
committed right inside ALO
and you had no idea it was even happening.
You're right—we dropped the
ball and I'm sorry about that.
It's no excuse.
But by the time we found out what
Nobuyuki Sugo was up to, using those
300 comatose SAO players as
guinea pigs, guinea pigs,
you'd already gone in
and taken care of it.
But why couldn't you stop
him from doing it in the
first place?
It's not like we weren't
keeping tabs on him.
Sugo worked in the same research lab as
Kayaba.
But there were 6,000 players coming
back from SAO that needed us.
We were swamped,
checking up on their health and getting
them adjusted to the real world again.
Our staff was stretched so thin,
monitoring Sugo took a back seat.
That said,
none of us even considered
the possibility of him
building a lab inside the
game for his experiments.
And in the real world,
he gave us no indication he was
involved with anything shady.
Why don't you tell me what happened
in there?
For starters, how do you
know what Sugo was up to?
It's not like I suspected
anything, Not at first.
This is Sugo.
He's our company's director of R &D.
I'm Nobuyuki Sugo.
It's a pleasure.
I'm Kazuto Kirigaya.
Kazuto, take care.
I heard you and Asuna
were lovers in the game.
Is that true?
Uh-huh.
That is unfortunate.
It's going to make for one complicated
relationship between you and I.
In case you're curious, her father and
I were discussing her marriage to me.
Stop it!
Who do you think you are?
You can't take advantage of
Asuna like this Take advantage?
Oh, please.
If anything, I have a right to her!
Perhaps I should explain why?
Any idea what happened to Argus?
They're the company that developed SAO.
I heard they closed it down.
Very good!
The lawsuits and damages they
had to pay took their toll.
The company was forced into bankruptcy.
But the maintenance of the SAO
servers was given to another company.
An electronics manufacturer, where
Asuna's father, Shozo Yuki, is the CEO.
Wrecked progress.
And I work for the company's
full-dive technology R &D division.
In other words, and without
getting into specifics,
you could say I'm the
one keeping Asuna alive.
Now I ask you, is it wrong for me to expect
a little compensation for my trouble?
I don't know what kind of promises
you made to each other in the game,
and I don't really care.
But I don't ever want to see
you here again. Understood?
And from now on, stay
away from the Yuki family.
We're having the ceremony here
on January 26th, a week from now.
Save the date.
Even though you're not welcome here
anymore, you should come to the wedding.
No need to thank me.
Well, Mr.
Hero, you've got the
room all to yourself now.
Say goodbye and get out.
Jeez.
Geez.
Didn't you think he was
suspicious after that?
No, because all I could
think about was Asuna.
Then a friend showed me a screenshot
with an avatar that looked like her,
but that was my only clue.
And based on that, you dove
into ALO to try and save her?
Well, it was all I had to go
on, and that was enough for me.
I need your help again.
One more time.
Link, start!
I'm back in another game, even after
everything I just went through.
Ugh!
Oh!
Oh! Huh?
Hey, Yui.
It's me.
You remember?
I do.
I remember you, Daddy.
Yui!
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
You're back.
It's a miracle.
Listen, Yui.
I think your mommy might
be stuck in here somewhere.
Mommy? Really?
What do you mean she's stuck?
After SAO was cleared, Asuna
never woke up in the real world.
I found out she was seen in Alfheim.
There's a picture, but
it's too blurry to tell.
What are we going to do?
What are you doing? Go! Get out of here!
Would someone tell me why three big
guys are fighting one single girl?
That's pretty uncool if you ask me.
What did you say?
You better get your ass out of here, noob.
Fast!
Now, if I remember correctly, the player
called Leafa is your younger sister, right?
Yeah, she's the last person I ever expected
to run into an ALO, especially that way.
No way!
You just swam 25 meters
like it was nothing!
You even got your
breathing technique down.
You got the hang of it fast.
You are a good athlete.
It's all thanks to you guys.
What's up?
Are you starting to miss your
big brother or something?
No, not at all.
I was just wondering why he's so late.
I don't have a brother or sister,
but I always wished I had one.
Being close with him is nothing
to be embarrassed about.
You think so? Mm-hmm.
Well, the thing is, before
he got trapped inside SAO,
we weren't really all that close.
I wanted to see what those VR Miss he
was so obsessed with were all about.
That's why I started playing ALO.
He's the reason I'm
such a badass gamer now.
Kirito said he needed help getting to the
World Tree, and you showed him the way.
Yeah, but when I first met him in
there, I had no idea he was my brother.
He came off like just
another obnoxious gamer.
I kind of thought he was a dork, because
sometimes he'd get all broody and emo.
But the weird thing is, I hung around.
I don't know why I did, but I did.
Daddy?
Sorry.
It's just that I have to get to the
top of the world tree as soon as I can.
Okay, what's the rush?
I'm sort of looking for someone.
What do you mean?
No offense, but it's hard to explain.
Thank you, Leafa.
All the info you gave me
is really going to help.
Wait.
Are you heading for the
World Tree right now?
Uh-huh.
I need to see for myself.
Alone that's crazy it's
really far away and
you'll have to fight a bunch of monsters.
I know you can handle yourself but.
Hey if you want i can take you there.
The world tree was way far i can't believe
we made it in three
days it was crazy tough.
Thank you for helping him, Tsukaha.
No, you don't have to thank me.
I actually had a blast.
It was tough, but it was fun
going on an adventure with Kirito.
Hey, you getting tired yet?
No, I'm good to go.
Okay, Mr. Tough Guy.
I hate to break it to you, but flying's
out for both of us for a little while.
Huh? How come?
You see that mountain way over there?
It's above the altitude
limit, so we can't fly over.
The only way anyone can pass
it is to go through the caves.
It's the toughest part of the trip
between Sylph Territory and Arun.
Or so I've heard.
I've never even been this far myself.
Guess we walk.
These caves, are they long? Pretty long.
There's a mining town about halfway.
It's neutral territory,
so we can rest there.
That reminds me.
Are you good for time, or
do you have to get back?
It's seven at night in the real world.
Yeah, I can keep going for a while.
Cool.
I can too, so let's keep going.
But since we're here,
we should rotate out.
Wait, rotate? Yeah.
We take turns logging out and
resting while the other keeps watch.
You can't log out when you're
in the field, remember?
So we have to take turns logging out.
The person who stays behind
guards the other's avatar.
Okay, sounds like a plan.
Ladies first.
I can't wait to get back there.
Kirito...
It's not that I'm in love
with him or anything,
or that I've got someone
to go on adventures with.
No, I'm just excited I get
to go places in a new world.
So, what'd you think of him after that?
You still didn't know who he was, right?
Did you think he was awesome or what?
I don't know about awesome.
I guess, if anything, I
thought he was really fast.
Later on, I saw how focused
he was during battle,
Way more than anyone I'd ever seen before.
That's enough, Kirito!
If we lose, it'll just mean a
couple extra hours of flying!
Let's give up while we can!
No way.
As long as I'm alive, I'm not
gonna let anyone in my party die.
I won't let that happen again.
What the hell what's he
doing when I realized
why he took those battles so seriously?
Because there was someone he was trying to
protect I thought this is
a guy I can believe in.
It's just a game in the end anything goes
right if you want to kill you kill if
you want to steal you steal a lot of
people think like that more than I care to
know and in a way I get it even I used
to think like that but none of it's true
in a virtual world there's things you have
to protect because it's a virtual world
someone special taught me that
if you give into your impulses
in here it's It's gonna change
who you are in the real world.
The player and the character
are one and the same.
Leafa, you're a good person,
and I wanna be your friend.
So it doesn't matter what the reason is.
There's no way in hell I'd ever
attack a friend for my own benefit.
I couldn't live with myself.
It didn't matter what the odds were.
My brother would never turn his back on
a fight if it was for the right thing.
That's why I knew he could
never lose. Ah! Kirito!
No!
You know, I think it's great
you guys are close and all,
but I get the feeling you're a little
too close, know what I'm saying?
God, what are you talking about?
Anyway, shouldn't I
get back to practicing?
You heard the lady.
Let's get back to it.
If only I'd known before I fell in love.
Is that you?
Kazutou?
Huh?
Sugu?
Suguha?
I can't believe it.
It's not fair!
No!
Sugu!
I...
I betrayed the feelings I had!
I betrayed the love I felt for you.
When I met Kirito,
I thought finally I could give up on
all these feelings I have for you.
What the hell?
I already had!
But now I'm...
Well, I mean love?
But you and me, we're...
No, we're not.
I said no, we're not!
I know you're not really my
brother and I'm not your sister.
I've known all along, for
the last two years anyway.
That's why you quit Kendo, isn't it?
And why you started avoiding me?
It's because you knew the
whole time, didn't you?
You pushed me away because I'm
not your real sister, didn't you?
You did.
Well, if that's how it is,
why do you care about me now?
I just...
I was so happy you came back from SAO.
I was happy because you were being nice to
me again, just like when we were little.
It felt like you were
finally giving me a chance.
That's what I thought.
But now, if this is how it is, I wish
you'd kept on being a jerk to me.
If you had, I wouldn't have
realized how I felt about you.
I wouldn't have felt sad and
jealous when I found out about her.
And I wouldn't have tried forgetting about
you and falling in love
with Kinito instead!
I'm sorry.
Go on.
Leave me alone.
Oh
What are you doing?
Look, I wanted to apologize.
But I just didn't know
how to go about doing it.
So I was going to throw the duel.
You were
I'm sorry
I'm sorry too
I think my problem is I never really
came back to the real world after SAO
and I can't come back until she wakes up
in a way the game hasn't ended for me yet
and I guess that's why?
I still haven't figured out how
I fit in at home or with you.
Not yet, anyway.
And when you do, I'll be there.
It doesn't matter how long it takes.
I'll be waiting for the day
you come back to us for real.
Until then, I'll help you in here.
Hey, Suguha?
You won't learn how to
swim unless you practice!
Yeah, I'm coming.
Okay, so thanks to your sister's help.
You finally reached the world tree.
In the report it says Sugo's grand quest?
Was designed to be impossible to clear.
But somehow you cleared it on your own!
And went on to rescue Asuna.
No, that's not how it happened.
I didn't clear it alone.
I'm almost there!
Just a little further?
Ah!
Cats!
Outro music
No way!
He's using a dark magic spell!
Okay, Dragoons, get ready
to choke these suckers!
Stealth warriors, prepare
to engage the enemy!
Fire breath, attack!
Fenrir storm, fire at will!
I cleared the quest, thanks to
Leafa and Recon, Sakuya and Alicia,
and all the Sylph and Cats warriors.
If it wasn't for them, I would have
never been able to reach Asuna.
I see.
And then Sugo, a .k .a.
Oberon the Fairy King, appeared.
Usually I wouldn't think it possible
for a player to beat the Game Master.
But then, you're an unusual player.
Yes!
Great!
Ha!
That's what I was hoping for!
You can't get NPC girls
to make faces like that!
Ah, you smell lovely.
Figuring out how to replicate the way
you smell in real life was a challenge.
And don't even get me
started on how hard it was to
get an analyzer into your
hospital room undetected.
Get away from her!
She's so cool!
Give me a break.
Why don't you stay down and
grovel like a good little doggy?
Cait!
System command, change the pain
absorber from level 10 to level 8.
Hurts, doesn't it?
I'll increase the pain gradually to
give you something to look forward to.
By the way,
once it drops below level three, it'll
start affecting your body in the real world.
As for you...
Yummy. How sweet.
Sugou!
You bastard!
You BASTARD!
I'll kill you! You hear?
I'm gonna kill you!
Are you giving up?
No.
I'm facing reality.
Then you are giving up.
To the power of a system you once defied.
What choice do I have?
I'm just a player.
And he's the GM.
Then our battle was... What? A joke?
Do you remember how
you showed me the power
of the human will was
superior to the system?
How you showed me the
possibilities of the future?
You're...
Get up, Kirito. Get up!
GMs are the supreme rulers
of the worlds they create.
And as long as they're in that world,
they can access the powers
of a god if they want.
The thing is, it's the system
that gives them their power.
It's not something they
had to win or hone.
But real power is something
that's only found in you.
That's true in the virtual
world, and the real one.
You wanna go get some ice cream?
Sounds ice, am I right?
In the end, Sugo overestimated
the power he got.
That's why he self-destructed.
That he did.
As for what happened next, you know
everything there is to know about that.
I better get going.
I'm supposed to meet the
others in ALO after this.
I don't want to be late.
Before you go, I have one more question.
I heard about something called the Seed.
Have you heard of it?
Yeah, of course.
See you around, Kirito.
You know what, Kirito?
I never appreciated the difference between
in-game time and real-world
time as I do now. Why?
Because it's night IRL right now?
No, because it's a perfect
day at the beach here!
Those blue skies!
and that white sand, and those gentle
waves, and that warm sun, and that view.
What's up, dogs?
Sorry I'm late.
What?
You got a problem with my suit?
Oh, no, it's the incoming wave!
We are multiple feet ahead!
I'll get you back!
Pain, show her your water breath!
Higher at will!
Behold, the power of Rita!
She's taking care good!
Leafa, you gonna be okay or
do you need more practice?
No, I'm good to go.
I'm not afraid anymore.
or as long as I can touch the bottom.
Well, you look more confident.
Oh, about where we're going today.
Yeah, I was gonna ask you, any idea how
far under this dungeon's supposed to be?
Pretty far down.
I think I heard it was
around a hundred meters.
A hundred?
I'm okay, I can do this.
It's for Yui, after all.
Thanks a lot, Leafa.
And then, the second Kirito saw the king
of all fish come storming out of the lake,
he screamed so loud!
Oh, ahhh!
Come on, you're so exaggerating.
I went, whoa, but that's
about as loud as I got.
Lucky, I wish I could have
seen the king of fish, too.
Don't worry, once the new
Aincrad opens up on floor 22,
we're going to buy another cabin and
have another contest at the lake.
Wait till you see it.
That fish is so ginormous, it's scary.
So scary, you might cry.
Oh, no I won't!
You say it's big, but when you
factor in the area of the lake,
it can't possibly be as big
as a whale in the real world!
Wait, have you seen a real whale before?
No, I just estimated the size of one
using measurements and video data I found.
I wish I could see real
world things like you two,
but since I can't, I just
have to make do with my data.
I see.
You poor thing.
If only Alfheim had whales.
I know you'd get a kick out of them.
They really are gigantic.
They jump out of the ocean and land
with a big splash and - Hold the phone!
What is it?
I just remembered something. That's right.
In the south of Sylph Territory, there's
supposed to be a quest with a whale in it.
Oh, can we go?
If we went, then maybe
I'd get to ride a whale.
That's probably not a good idea.
Hey, Kirito, you absolutely 100
% sure this quest is for real?
Because if not, man, you're
going to break Yui's heart.
If it turns out to be a
jellyfish or a sea butterfly,
it's going to be lamer than hell.
If it's a giant sea butterfly,
that would still be pretty rad.
You find anything on it, Eggiel?
Not much.
The quest's way out on
the edge of the world map.
I tried, man, but there's not a whole
lot of people who know about it.
Only thing I could confirm
is the part about a big-ass
sea monster showing up at the
end that's all so at least
we got something to look
forward to come on let's hit
this hey guys it's time we
start saddling up for the quest
okay
Oh, uh, are you going to
wear your armor on the quest?
Duh, of course.
We are going into battle.
Hurry up and change and
we'll leave you behind.
Okay, so...
If you guys don't mind, I'd like
to be the party leader for today.
You all know our objective,
so if anyone sees a whale out there,
call it out and follow my lead.
Thanks, you guys.
I really appreciate this. Okay, then.
You ready? Yeah!
According to these
coordinates, it should be here.
Hey, is that it over there?
Okay, everyone, I'm gonna cast
a water-breathing spell for us.
Ah! What?
Lima!
Wow, look at that!
Hey, I think I see someone down there.
Nice, we got an NPC waiting for us.
Dude, if we're on an undersea quest,
then I bet that NPC's a mermaid!
Don't worry, Miss Mermaid!
Klein's coming to save you!
Here I am, my lady.
My name's...
That's not a mermaid.
That's a grandpa.
Let's see what this gentleman wants.
Greetings, fairies from the surface world.
Could you possibly help
an old man with a dilemma?
Is something wrong, Leafa?
Oh, no.
I just noticed the old man's name.
I think I've seen it somewhere before.
Some thieves have stolen a present I
acquired for an old friend of mine.
The temple behind me is their hideout.
Could you please retrieve it for
me before the rascals return?
We'd be happy to help.
I am most grateful, kind fairy.
The item in question is a pearl
about this size. Cha-ching!
I hope you're not thinking
about swiping it and selling it.
No, not this time, anyway.
I'm counting on you, my noble fairies.
If you succeed in retrieving the
pearl, I will reward you handsomely.
Okay, so it looks like this
will be a search and seize.
But there might be monsters
in there, so stay sharp.
If you're in the vanguard,
your sword strokes will be slower
underwater, so compensate for that.
And rearguard, don't even think about
using any lightning spells. Right!
Okay, guys, let's move out.
Hey, uh, Kirito, I don't think Leafa's
cool with this underwater stuff.
Shouldn't you, like, keep a
closer eye on her or something?
You okay?
Yeah, you're right, I should.
But it's so weird between us.
If it's just her and
me, everything's cool.
But if we're in a party
together, it's crazy awkward.
What are you talking about?
She's your sister.
All you have to do is be
yourself and look out for her.
You know, like a big brother.
I know.
But when I first met her
in-game, I didn't even realize...
Yo, you gotta be straight
up blind to miss that pit.
Dumb asses.
I can't believe he used to be a
top player in the assault team.
It doesn't matter to me.
I think he's rad no
matter how clumsy he is.
Daddy, in front of you!
Is that the whale?
No.
Not even close.
Attack!
The head doesn't take damage.
I'll keep it busy!
You guys attack its flakes!
Aim on it! Copy that!
Come on, let's go help them. Okay.
I'm going.
Leafa!
Stay back with Asuna
and hit it with spells!
After everyone went to all
that trouble coaching me.
Thanks a bunch, Leafa!
What am I doing standing here?
I said I'd follow my brother anywhere!
Leafa, I'll be fine, I can do this!
Lisa!
Kirito! Do something!
Kirito! What are you doing?
Hey! Ah!
Oh yeah, when I was little,
I fell into a pond. And...
I remember sinking...
and then...
Sugou!
Asada!
I got you!
Ah!
Kazuto, you saved me again.
Oh, man.
I don't care if I never see another
stupid shrimp or crab again.
Or a squid or octopus.
After all that, we never did
get to see a whale. That sucks.
Yeah, maybe.
But Yui sure looked
like she was having fun.
Here you go.
We got it back for you.
Thank you.
This is wonderful.
Anyone else think it's
weird that we never saw
those thieves the old
man was talking about?
Yeah.
No! Don't give it to him!
What?
Look, it's not a pearl, it's an egg.
What the hell?
Plunderers of the deep sea.
Hold on, does that mean us?
If you don't mind, I'll
take possession of that.
If you won't hand it over,
you'll leave me no choice.
Kraken!
The sea demon from Norse mythology!
A thousand thanks, my little fairies.
You have retrieved the
egg of the royal child.
If not for the magic barrier,
I would have done it myself.
Now then, hand it over immediately.
You old coot.
We will not.
We're going to put the egg
right back where we found it.
In that case, you little pests, prepare
to spend eternity in a watery grave.
Look out!
Ahhhh!
Daddy, the stats of that
octopus are unbelievably high!
I don't think there's a single floor boss
in New Aincrad with stats as high as that.
I know that spear.
It's been a long time, old friend.
I see you're still up to your old tricks.
And I see you are still playing
lapdog to the minions of Aesir.
You disgrace your title, Lord of the Sea.
I am Lord of the Sea, and
you are in my backyard.
Now, do you really wish to
fight me, Lord of the Abyss?
I shall withdraw for now,
but take heed, old friend.
This is not over.
Soon, I shall claim
the power of the child.
Then I will rise up against Aesir.
Mark my words!
That is the egg of the one who will
someday rule over the seas and the sky.
I shall take it to a new resting place
where it will be safe from treachery.
Okay, what the hell's
going on? Is that it?
We clear it or what?
I'm lost too.
Does anyone know what the big guy
and the octopus were talking about?
It was not important.
Now, my noble fairies, I shall
transport you back to your own world.
Um, what do you mean by transport?
Hey, Peeta, isn't this whale gigantic?
Oh, yeah!
and
I'll
keep my mind
I'll see you
next
time.
Thank you so much for your
love and love. Thank you.
Thank you.